{
  "meta": {
    "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
    "perDifficulty": 20,
    "createdAt": "2026-01-17T09:57:32.275375"
  },
  "problems": {
    "1": [
      {
        "id": "P4769797325573569",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "18 - (6) = ?",
        "answer": "12",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7534751250593859",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "30 - (-8) = ?",
        "answer": "38",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5382205676102315",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "24 - (27) = ?",
        "answer": "-3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4882294775502505",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "17 + (4) = ?",
        "answer": "21",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P0290248199467152",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-13 - (-3) = ?",
        "answer": "-10",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7241813776272887",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-9 - (12) = ?",
        "answer": "-21",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9807219775189232",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "23 + (-1) = ?",
        "answer": "22",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5918927756279109",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "4 - (-29) = ?",
        "answer": "33",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6427496480093358",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "12 + (-29) = ?",
        "answer": "-17",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1817290265134321",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-22 - (25) = ?",
        "answer": "-47",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2116602842114815",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-14 - (-6) = ?",
        "answer": "-8",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2782566156388060",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-10 - (-9) = ?",
        "answer": "-1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2522715317823806",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "30 - (23) = ?",
        "answer": "7",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7490242610828507",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-25 + (0) = ?",
        "answer": "-25",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2242221657197481",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-27 - (30) = ?",
        "answer": "-57",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7542332040595262",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-26 + (19) = ?",
        "answer": "-7",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8392288462845982",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "30 + (-15) = ?",
        "answer": "15",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1262209748742062",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "9 + (-21) = ?",
        "answer": "-12",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4650339834352207",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "12 + (-23) = ?",
        "answer": "-11",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1677891433678022",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 1,
        "question": "-14 - (19) = ?",
        "answer": "-33",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      }
    ],
    "2": [
      {
        "id": "P9647207730340876",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(7)×(11) = ?",
        "answer": "77",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5757967284124141",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(-18)÷(2) = ?",
        "answer": "-9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5920978612498522",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(0)×(0) = ?",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8502932390887963",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(24)÷(3) = ?",
        "answer": "8",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3472037653084490",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(7)×(-9) = ?",
        "answer": "-63",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5059607896770779",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(1)×(9) = ?",
        "answer": "9",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1055388706439985",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(-16)÷(8) = ?",
        "answer": "-2",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4354871450076770",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(-1)×(8) = ?",
        "answer": "-8",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6159123540535510",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(132)÷(12) = ?",
        "answer": "11",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4355744930038943",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(45)÷(9) = ?",
        "answer": "5",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8517131600193318",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(66)÷(6) = ?",
        "answer": "11",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7504762818270062",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(-10)×(-4) = ?",
        "answer": "40",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3363966198913752",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(72)÷(12) = ?",
        "answer": "6",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2121198501797390",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(12)÷(4) = ?",
        "answer": "3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5557910279195838",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(-24)÷(6) = ?",
        "answer": "-4",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7200746641041943",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(4)×(-6) = ?",
        "answer": "-24",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6459028997409523",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(15)÷(5) = ?",
        "answer": "3",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P2942355813204973",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(3)×(2) = ?",
        "answer": "6",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6639600215968160",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(0)÷(5) = ?",
        "answer": "0",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4255038127052147",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 2,
        "question": "(-10)÷(10) = ?",
        "answer": "-1",
        "answerType": "number",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      }
    ],
    "3": [
      {
        "id": "P7028549421857689",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "11/6 + -2/4 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "4/3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1206558847523058",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-4/4 + -4/3 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-7/3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9508775603934348",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-6/4 + -9/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7386046535089507",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "10/3 + -6/3 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "4/3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5967907405123017",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-4/6 + 12/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "4/3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P3608810691493864",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-9/3 + -3/3 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-4",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1265829598479816",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-3/2 + 10/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "1/6",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6974173929101944",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-11/2 + 5/4 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-17/4",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P5740642196263323",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-8/5 + -9/2 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-61/10",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1843636703900817",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "3/5 + 2/4 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "11/10",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8221156452994304",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-11/4 + 3/2 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-5/4",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6294457069519983",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "0/5 + -10/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-5/3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P9491256423580312",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-11/3 + -8/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-5",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7644434453261942",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-10/3 + -9/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-29/6",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P7756935396982173",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "7/6 + 7/3 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "7/2",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P8601666658261801",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "0/5 + 2/4 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "1/2",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P0602303043725408",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "1/4 + 6/6 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "5/4",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P6255150304066032",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "11/2 + 12/3 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "19/2",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P1738135483264344",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-4/2 + -7/3 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-13/3",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      },
      {
        "id": "P4505037046177024",
        "unitId": "m1-1-1-II-1",
        "difficulty": 3,
        "question": "-10/3 + -12/5 = ? (기약분수)",
        "answer": "-86/15",
        "answerType": "string",
        "tolerance": 0,
        "unitLabel": "",
        "hint": "",
        "explain": "",
        "tags": []
      }
    ]
  }
}